So far, we've looked at policy-based methods that
到目前为止 我们讨论了仅使用策略的优势部分
only use the goodness of a policy as the objective function,
作为目标函数的基于策略的方法
that is, how much reward we expect to get out of it.
即我们预期从中获得多少奖励
What this means is that we are not bothered with what actions the policy takes,
意思是我们不关心该策略采取了什么操作
what states at visits,
经历了什么状态
how frequently, et cetera.
频率有多大 等等
All we care about is the overall expected reward.
我们只关心整体预期奖励
This can result in two policies that are
这样可以形成
close to each other in the objective function space,
在目标函数空间内非常接近
but wildly different in the way they behave.
但是行为截然不同的两个策略
Let's take a four-legged walking robot as an example.
我们来举一个有四条腿的行走机器人例子
One policy might make the robot walk this way,
一个策略可能使机器人这样行走
while another policy might make it walk with this completely different gait.
另一个策略可能使机器人的步法完全不一样
Both policies are reasonable solutions.
两个策略都是合理的解决方案
Let's assume policy A is our current policy,
假设策略 A 是当前策略
and policy B is the direction that our
策略 B 是梯度目标指向的策略
objective of gradient points toward, a better policy.
一个更好的策略
Our optimization algorithm will try to update the parameters to move from A towards B,
我们的优化算法将尝试更新参数以从 A 移到 B
but not all the way,
但是并非一直这样
since we use a learning step, alpha.
因为我们使用了学习步骤 α
So, we land up with some intermediate set of policy parameters,
因此我们进入一组中间策略参数
but these may result in very poor performance.
但是可能会导致很糟糕的性能
This is very common in complex control tasks like walking,
这在行走等复杂的控制任务中很常见
where the coordination and timing between different actions is very important.
不同动作之间的坐标和时间非常重要
The algorithm is still learning to improve the policy and arrive at something reasonable,
算法依然在学习改善策略并获得合理的结果
but the learning process itself can be very unstable and inefficient.
但是学习流程本身可能会非常不稳定并且效率很低
Moreover, in certain applications like robotics,
此外 在某些应用中 例如机器人
where we are dealing with electro mechanical components,
我们会处理电子机械组件
drastic changes in policy parameters may literally break things.
显著改变策略参数可能会破坏装置
For these reasons, we should pay attention to
因为这些原因
the policy parameters in addition to the objective function.
除了目标函数之外 我们还应该注意策略参数
In fact, we might want to play some constraints on the policy parameters,
实际上 我们可能需要对策略参数进行一些限制
that you are only allowed to change the parameters in
只能以某种方式更改参数
a certain way or by a certain amount.
或只能按照一定的数量更改参数
This can be implemented in our gradient-based algorithms by adding a constraint,
我们可以通过添加限制条件 在基于梯度的算法中实现这一点
that the difference between two policies is at most some threshold, delta.
要求两个策略之间的差异不能超过某个阈值 δ
Another way to introduce this constraint is to
另一个添加这种限制条件的方式是
add a penalty term to the objective function,
向目标函数添加惩罚项
that is sum multiple of this difference.
即该差异的某个乘数
If we try to optimize for this combined objective function,
如果我们尝试优化这个组合的目标函数
then we'll be driven towards policies that are better,
那么我们将能够获得更好的策略
but not too different at each step.
但是在每一步差别并不是很大
This helps stabilize the learning algorithm and it's kind of
这样可以使学习算法很稳定
like adding regularization to machine learning algorithms.
有点像对机器学习算法进行正则化
But in both these approaches,
但是对于这两种方法
whether we add a constraint or a penalty,
无论是添加限制条件还是惩罚项
we need some way to quantify the difference between two policies.
我们都需要某种方式来量化两个策略之间的差异
A naive way to compute the difference between two policies is to use the difference
计算两个策略之间的差异的一种简单方式是
between their parameter vectors and take the norm of the difference, say Euclidean norm.
算出两组参数向量之间的差异并对该差异取范数 例如欧几里得范数
If your policies are some complex function of the parameters which is
如果你的策略是某个复杂的参数函数
indeed the case when using deep neural networks or other machine learning models,
当你使用深度神经网络或其他机器学习模型时就是这种情况
then the parameter difference may not accurately
那么参数差异可能无法准确地反映
reflect the difference between how the policies behave,
策略行为之间的差异
what actions they ultimately produce.
以及它们最终生成的动作之间的差异
In order to come up with a better distance measure,
为了得出一个更好的差异衡量方式
we need to think about a policy as a probability distribution over actions.
我们需要想出一个用到不同动作的概率分布的策略
This perspective is especially useful when we have a continuous action space.
当动作空间是连续空间时 这个思考角度尤其有用
Consider the continuous version of the cart pull problem,
思考下拖车问题的连续版本
where you no longer have binary actions for left and right.
不再有向左和向右的二元动作
Instead, you can apply any amount of force between minus one and plus one,
你可以应用在 -1 到 +1 之间的任何大小的力
like minus 0.5 or plus 0.8.
例如 -0.5 或 +0.8
Our policy is the probability distribution over this range of actions.
我们的策略是这个动作范围的概率分布
Note that the distribution can be different from state to state.
注意 不同状态之间的分布可能不相同
If we have continuous states,
如果是连续状态
we can unify these into
我们可以将这些分布统一成
a single continuous distribution over the combined range of states and actions.
一个状态和动作组合范围的连续分布
Consider that we have two such policies,
假设有两个这样的策略
each is a distribution over states and actions.
每个都是状态和动作分布
Now, how do we compare these distributions?
如何比较这两个分布？
One statistical measure we can use is the Kullback Leibler, or KL divergence.
一种统计学衡量方法是 KL 散度
The KL divergence of p with respect to q,
p 相对于 q 的 KL 散度
is defined as the integral of p of x,
定义为 p(x) 的积分
times log of p of x by q of x.
乘以 p(x)/q(x) 的对数
We can rewrite log p of x by q of x as log p of x minus log q of x,
我们可以将 log p(x)/q(x) 变换成 log p(x) - log q(x)
which might make it easier to understand.
这样可能更容易理解
Here are the original distributions,
这是原始分布
p of x and q of x.
p(x) 和 q(x)
We take the log of the two probabilities,
我们取这两个概率的对数
and then at each point x,
然后在每个点 x
we take the difference between these log probabilities.
我们将这两个对数概率相减
Finally, we scale the difference by one of
最后 我们用某个概率值缩放该差值
the probability values and sum that up over the entire range of x.
并在整个 x 的范围内求和
Intuitively, this is the area of
从图中可以看出
the non-overlapping region between the two log probability distributions,
该区域是这两个对数概率分布的非重叠区域
but summed up at each location x,
但是使用其中一个概率作为参考
using one of the probabilities as a reference.
在每个位置 x 求和
Which means, the KL divergence of p with respect to q,
意味着 p 相对于 q 的 KL 散度
is not equal to that of q to p. It is an asymmetric distance measure.
不等于 q 相对于 p 的散度 这是一个非对称距离衡量法
The way we apply this to policy gradients is,
我们将其应用到策略梯度的方式是
we compute the KL divergence between the current policy, theta,
计算当前策略 θ 与任何新候选策略 θ′
and any new candidate policy, theta-prime,
之间的 KL 散度
and then we use this difference term as the constraint part of our objective function.
然后使用这个差异项作为目标函数的限制条件
This term punishes new policies that change the behavior too much.
该项会惩罚使行为变化很大的新策略
So, the new policy has to produce that much more value to be considered better.
因此 新策略必须带来更多价值 才能被视为更好的策略
In the context of the overall policy gradients algorithm,
对于总体策略梯度算法
this helps create a more stable learning process
这有助于创建一个更稳定的学习流程
where the policy is not jumping around as much.
策略不会大幅度跳动
Several variance of constraint policy gradients have been developed,
目前已经开发出了多个受限策略梯度变体版本
including the popular trust region policy optimization,
包括热门的置信域策略优化
or TRPO algorithm, and more recently,
简称 TRPO 算法
proximal policy optimization or PPO.
以及最近的近端策略优化 (PPO)
Here's PPO being applied to a really hard environment.
这是将 PPO 应用到一个非常复杂的环境示例
The agent is trying to reach a target, the pink ball.
智能体尝试接触一个目标 即粉色球
All the while, learning to walk, run, turn,
同时学习如何行走 跑步 转身
recover from minor hits,
从小挫折中恢复
and how to stand up from the ground when it is knocked over.
以及如何在跌倒后站起来
This demonstrates how the ability to play with
这个示例演示了修改目标函数
the objective function allows us to build in several kinds of constraints,
使我们能够内置多种限制条件
including additional losses that can further guide our agent's learning.
包括额外的损失函数 从而进一步指导智能体学习规律